<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>writing: retirement</title>
    <link href="/2022/07/11/writing-retirement/"/>
    <url>/2022/07/11/writing-retirement/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Topic"><a href="#Topic" class="headerlink" title="Topic"></a>Topic</h1><p>Today, more people are living longer after they retire from work. What problems will it cause for individuals and society? What can be done to prevent it?</p><h2 id="Writing"><a href="#Writing" class="headerlink" title="Writing"></a>Writing</h2><p><strong>Thanks</strong> to improved standards of medical treatment and health care,modern citizens are expected to live much longer after retirement than ever. Consequently,this may incur several repercussions on both individuals and society as a whole, and this thorny issue can be resolved promisingly.</p><p><strong>As</strong> for senior citizens,the leisure work-free life can be relaxing and refreshing for the first couple of years after retirement,but with the lapse of time, the lack of self-fulfillment from work can frequently cause boredom. Besides, as most of their children are wrapped up in their work, the senior left at home alone are very likely to lack companionship and suffer from empty-nest syndrome. And they may even feel abandoned by society as the technology is progressing so fast that they fail to adapt to such a fast-paced life.</p><p><strong>On</strong> the social level, the government ought to allocate more budgets to pensions and other welfare services like hospitals and nursing houses for the ensuring retirees’ wellbeing, which indicates a heavier  financial burden on society. The trend has been proved that, referring to countries like Japan, the proportion of labor force reduces over periods, the increased expenditure on social welfare and health care for longevity, as well as the burden shifted onto the shoulders of the youth as they each would have to support more aged citizens.</p><p><strong>Given</strong> the gravity of these problems, two schemes can be put on the agenda. The first imperative approach is that the government can issue corresponding policies, such as raising the age of retirement, or encourage companies to reemploy those experienced senior workers. Taking full advantage of their abundant experience in workplace, the elderly can help to train new employees who lack relevant experience, which not only gives the old a sense of fulfilment but also alleviates the financial burden of the government to some extent. Additionally, communities can arrange a variety of activities for the senior community members. For instance, easy tasks like putting up notices can be assigned, which will make the old feel that they can still make contributions to the community.</p><p><strong>To</strong> recapitulate, since possible effects and feasible remedies have been enumerated, this crisis can be handled with joint efforts of both the government and communities.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>IELTS</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Writing: sources</title>
    <link href="/2022/07/11/Writing-sources/"/>
    <url>/2022/07/11/Writing-sources/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Topic"><a href="#Topic" class="headerlink" title="Topic"></a>Topic</h1><p>With the increasing demand for energy such as oil and gas, people start to look for their sources in remote and untouched places. Do the advantages outweigh the disadvantages?</p><h2 id="Writing"><a href="#Writing" class="headerlink" title="Writing"></a>Writing</h2><p>Global demand for energy is increasing rapidly due to population and economic growth. In order to meet these challenges, some suggest to find oil and gas in remote and untouched areas. Despite some environmental repercussions, I believe the benefits of this exploration are more significant.</p><p>I understand the environmental concerns raised by some people. They think that the local ecosystem would be destroyed. For example, the debate over whether to drill for energy in the Arctic and Antarctic has exited for more than a decade simply because of its possible disastrous impact. Drilling there would directly destroy the habitat of animals, such as polar bears and penguins to begin with. What is worse, a wider scale of energy exploration means over-dependence on fossil resources. Global warming and other climate problems have deteriorated to tipping point.</p><p>Nevertheless, these worries should not be overstated as the international community is fully aware of potential danger and in turn well prepared with relevant resolutions. There are already regulations and laws restricting reckless exploitation at both national and international levels, meaning that the risk and impacts could be meticulously monitored and kept at an acceptable level. As for global warming, we can solve it by developing new types of clean energy. For example, there is a large amount of solar energy for electric power generation, and thousands of wind turbines have also been erected in vast Grassland of Inner Mongolia for power energy. Through these new sustainable energy sources, we can reduce carbon emissions and achieve a low-carbon life.</p><p>Not to mention that if people stop exploring new sources of energy, it will trigger an economic crisis and even more serious social problems. The coming shortage could drive the price to high level that both people and companies are unable to afford. What comes next might be more severe problems that cloud threaten the normal function of society. Just like last winter, the Texas black out event caused 40% of the local residents to lose power. At the same time, Texas energy supplier Griddy had soared electricity prices from $50 per kilowatt-hour in the same period last year to more than $9000 per kilowatt-hour. And this caused a series of social problems.</p><p>In conclusion, with the consideration of economy and environment ,seeking for new sources in remote place has more benefits than disadvantages , both short-term and long-term.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>IELTS</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>writing for IELTS(2)</title>
    <link href="/2022/07/04/writing-for-IELTS-2/"/>
    <url>/2022/07/04/writing-for-IELTS-2/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Internet"><a href="#Internet" class="headerlink" title="Internet"></a>Internet</h1><h2 id="Life-quality"><a href="#Life-quality" class="headerlink" title="Life quality"></a>Life quality</h2><p>People living in 21st century have a better life quality than the people who lived in the previous centuries. To what extent do you agree or disagree?</p><h3 id="Mind-Mapping"><a href="#Mind-Mapping" class="headerlink" title="Mind Mapping"></a>Mind Mapping</h3><p><img src="/2022/07/04/writing-for-IELTS-2/life%20quality.png"></p><h3 id="Words-or-Sentences"><a href="#Words-or-Sentences" class="headerlink" title="Words or Sentences"></a>Words or Sentences</h3><p>First:</p><p>It is an undeniable fact that the world has been advancing rapidly since the beginning of this century. Therefore, many people opine that today our living standards are much better than those of our ancestors. l agree  with that ,which has manifold reasons to substantiate it.</p><p>Second:</p><p>Granted, quality of material life is being well-off. &#x2F;&#x2F;诚然，物质生活质量越来越小康</p><p>However, the mental problems cannot be ignored in contemporary. </p><p> sleep disorder, depression, and compulsive disorder &#x2F;&#x2F;睡眠障碍、抑郁症和强迫症的受害者</p><p>fast pace of living, heavier strain(沉重的压力） work and study pressure, and financial burden</p><p>Third and fourth:</p><p> high-speed rail,subway,and shared bikes</p><p>This allows people to reach any destination they desire in less time. </p><p>intelligent home appliance &#x2F;&#x2F;智能家电设施</p><p>better medical resources, improving contemporary people’s physical health.</p><p>For example, COVID-19 vaccine has decreased the rates of death; medicine for cancer can be treated effectively; surgery facility reduce the pain and body damage. Compared to the contemporary people, people in the past were more susceptible to diseases, causing that the fatality rate of infectious was high.</p><p>Fifth:</p><p>In short, the people who live in the present century are enjoying the benefits of better services in the health, transport and communication sectors. Therefore, I believe, we enjoy a better quality of life than our ancestors.</p><h1 id="Others"><a href="#Others" class="headerlink" title="Others"></a>Others</h1><h2 id="Urbanization"><a href="#Urbanization" class="headerlink" title="Urbanization"></a>Urbanization</h2><p>Many cities replace farmlands and parks with houses. Is it positive or negative?</p><h3 id="Mind-Mapping-1"><a href="#Mind-Mapping-1" class="headerlink" title="Mind Mapping"></a>Mind Mapping</h3><p><img src="/2022/07/04/writing-for-IELTS-2/Urbanization.png"></p><h3 id="Words-or-Sentences-1"><a href="#Words-or-Sentences-1" class="headerlink" title="Words or Sentences"></a>Words or Sentences</h3><p>First:</p><p>Some societies have seen the nature being destroyed by urbanization. However,whether it is a blessing or a curse is a controversial issue. I stand firmly on the side which thinks it is negative.  I regard this trend as short-sighted and detrimental.</p><p>Second:</p><p>extent alleviate the tension of house shortage &#x2F;&#x2F;缓解住房紧缺</p><p>With the sea of people flooding into metropolises for the sake of seeking greater employment possibilities and a higher standard of living, the demand for house supply is increasing at an overwhelming rate.  &#x2F;&#x2F;随着为了寻求更大的就业机会和更高的生活水平而涌入大都市的人群，对住房供应的需求正在以压倒性的速度增长。</p><p>Besides, since urbanization is an inevitable and irreversible trend, relocation of farmlands can make the area more fit the overall image of the modernized metropolitan city.  &#x2F;&#x2F;此外，由于城市化是一个不可避免和不可逆转的趋势，农田的搬迁可以使该地区更符合现代化大都市的整体形象。</p><p>Third and fourth:</p><p>The detriments that this development has must not be overlooked.</p><p>As one of the fundamental parts of amenities, parks usually function as the places for residents’ physical exercises and other leisure activities.</p><p>considering increasingly erratic weather patterns,political and economic upheavals, and ever more mouths to feed across the planet,prudent planning for the future would prioritize locally-grown food by preserving farmlands rather than destroying it for residential areas.</p><p>Fifth:</p><p>In conclusion, we can understand why many cities have already transformed the public parks in urban areas and farmlands in the outskirt into living complexes, but these cities will par for such action in the near future.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>IELTS</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Speaking for IELTS</title>
    <link href="/2022/06/30/Speaking-for-IELTS/"/>
    <url>/2022/06/30/Speaking-for-IELTS/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Person"><a href="#Person" class="headerlink" title="Person"></a>Person</h1><h2 id="famous-person"><a href="#famous-person" class="headerlink" title="famous person"></a>famous person</h2><h3 id="Mind"><a href="#Mind" class="headerlink" title="Mind"></a>Mind</h3><ol><li>描述人物：职业、外貌、第一次如何知道他</li><li>人物生平：出名前、出名中（因何而出名）、出名后（现状）</li><li>看法：feeling + eg</li></ol><h3 id="Messi"><a href="#Messi" class="headerlink" title="Messi"></a>Messi</h3><p>I would like to talk about Lionel Messi, the only player who has won a 7-time Ballon d’Or<sup id="fnref:1" class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote"><span class="hint--top hint--rounded" aria-label="金球奖">[1]</span></a></sup>.On the court, where professional players average about 183 in height, Messi looks so small at 170, but no one dares to ignore his role on the court. As for how I first got to know him, I still remember it. That happened in the 2007 season, Barcelona against Real Madrid, where 19 Messi scored his first career hat-trick.</p><p>Messi, whom we often know now, is the top player who has won 10 La Liga titles and 4 Champions League titles. But not many people know that when Messi was young, he almost gave up football because of a lack of growth hormone, but thanks to Barca’s timely intervention, which helped Messi pay for high treatment costs, the football player showed talent in the days to come. The fame and money that football brings has not addicted him to live a luxury and dissipation life. He is passionate about philanthropy and the construction of football in his hometown.</p><p>There are two reasons why l am interested in him. Firstly,l am obsessed with his superb football skills,which  is extremely watchable. Just like what l said before he is born for soccer. Secondly, his humility and unafraid of challenges inspire me. Peach and plum don’t say anything, but they are self-made<sup id="fnref:2" class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote"><span class="hint--top hint--rounded" aria-label="桃李不言，下自成蹊">[2]</span></a></sup>.In the end, I sincerely wish him to win the FIFA World Cup Trophy<sup id="fnref:3" class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote"><span class="hint--top hint--rounded" aria-label="大力神杯">[3]</span></a></sup> in this year.</p><iframe src="test1.pdf" width="800px" height="800px" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe><h3 id="Professor-Tang"><a href="#Professor-Tang" class="headerlink" title="Professor Tang"></a>Professor Tang</h3><p>l would like to talk about Professor Tang Yu. Perhaps he is not well known among the ordinary people of our country, but in our field of expertise he is a highly respected scholar. He is tall and slim, always wearing a pair of black-rimmed glasses, a standard scholarly demeanor. The first time I met him was in my junior year of college, where he taught us a course on big data science and technology. </p><p>Like many academics, he also studied abroad at a young age. After receiving his Ph.D. from MIT, he chose to return to China and eventually came to our school to teach. He is fascinated by the front-end technology of big data science , published many papers at home and abroad, and won the first prize of national science and technology.</p><p>Although he is a long-established professor, he is humble in class. Since learning about big data for the first time, I often asked him questions. These questions that may seem like idiots to him, but he were patiently answered for me. At the same time, his profound knowledge also deeply influenced me, so that I finally chose the path of big data science, and he was the guide on my learning path.</p><section class="footnotes"><div class="footnote-list"><ol><li><span id="fn:1" class="footnote-text"><span>金球奖<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref"> ↩</a></span></span></li><li><span id="fn:2" class="footnote-text"><span>桃李不言，下自成蹊<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref"> ↩</a></span></span></li><li><span id="fn:3" class="footnote-text"><span>大力神杯<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref"> ↩</a></span></span></li></ol></div></section>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>IELTS</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>writing for IELTS</title>
    <link href="/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/"/>
    <url>/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Internet"><a href="#Internet" class="headerlink" title="Internet"></a>Internet</h1><h2 id="Media"><a href="#Media" class="headerlink" title="Media"></a>Media</h2><p>More and more people no longer read newspaper or watch TV programs to get news. They get news about the world through the internet. Is this a positive or negative development ?</p><h3 id="Mind-Mapping"><a href="#Mind-Mapping" class="headerlink" title="Mind Mapping"></a>Mind Mapping</h3><p><img src="/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/Media.png" alt="Media"></p><h3 id="Words-or-Sentences"><a href="#Words-or-Sentences" class="headerlink" title="Words or Sentences"></a>Words or Sentences</h3><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">First:</span><br><span class="line">While I accept that surfing the internet to read news can sometimes have a positive effect on the user, I believe that it is more likely to have a harmful impact. </span><br><span class="line">Second:</span><br><span class="line">fragmented time //碎片化时间 like wolking time,have dinner in a restaurant and so on.</span><br><span class="line">The web is rich in resources, and you can search for more news you want to know. </span><br><span class="line">Internet does a great job in accelerating the circulation（加速传播） of the news.</span><br><span class="line">Third and fourth:</span><br><span class="line">Electrical newspapers make it a much more difficult thing to have deep reading and thorough thinking as they advocate fast and superficial reading with enormous information, while printed ones encourage slow and deep reading with proper amounts of exact information.</span><br><span class="line">To be specific, many pieces of news appearing on the Internet are inaccurate and unreliable, even the coverage towards the same event differs largely, which will consume readers or viewers a large amount of time and energy to ascertain the authenticity（确认真实性） of the news. By contrast, based on careful authorized steps and censorship（授权步骤和审查）, most of the resources from newspapers and TV programs are confirmed and dependable. Not to mention that traditional media can help people access the in-depth reports（深度报道）.</span><br><span class="line">Fifh:</span><br><span class="line">All in all, Internet has certainly revolutionised news propagation, but not all of the outcomes of this revolution have been positive.To some degree, getting news through printed newspapers or television are still irreplaceable.</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="Security-and-Convenience"><a href="#Security-and-Convenience" class="headerlink" title="Security and Convenience"></a>Security and Convenience</h2><h3 id="Mind-Mapping-1"><a href="#Mind-Mapping-1" class="headerlink" title="Mind Mapping"></a>Mind Mapping</h3><p><img src="/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/securityandconvenience.png" alt="securityandconvenience"></p><h3 id="Words-or-Sentences-1"><a href="#Words-or-Sentences-1" class="headerlink" title="Words or Sentences"></a>Words or Sentences</h3><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br><span class="line">16</span><br><span class="line">17</span><br><span class="line">18</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">First:</span><br><span class="line">Opinions on a digital society has been contradictory with severe tension and incompatibility between the concerns for data privacy and the pursuit of convenience.</span><br><span class="line">Second:</span><br><span class="line">vulnerability //弱点,攻击</span><br><span class="line">manipulate vt. 熟练操作</span><br><span class="line">hack into vi. 侵入（他人的计算机系统）</span><br><span class="line">vigilance n. 警惕（性）</span><br><span class="line">elaborate adj. 精心制作的</span><br><span class="line">fraud n. 诈骗</span><br><span class="line">Many argue that sensitive information registered online leads to the vulnerability of personal security and constant harassment. </span><br><span class="line">A minute after you browse certain applications, you get a call promoting their products immediately, and on a continuous basis. These side effects are eating up the benefits it can bring.</span><br><span class="line">Third and fourth:</span><br><span class="line">give up eating for fear of chocking.</span><br><span class="line">Simply a swipe on the phone allows us to pay without cash, to have the goods delivered to the door, and to keep in frequent contact with friends thousand miles away.</span><br><span class="line">Especially against the backdrop of the long-lasting pandemic, it is impossible to go anywhere without the green health code and travel records. </span><br><span class="line">Therefore, putting personal particulars online has become an irreversible trend, not only as the pathway towards personal convenience but also the necessity for social development.</span><br><span class="line">Fifh:</span><br><span class="line">In conclusion, I strongly believe that the advantages of storing personal information online have exceeded the risks and it complies with the requirement of social advancement.</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Education"><a href="#Education" class="headerlink" title="Education"></a>Education</h1><h2 id="Library"><a href="#Library" class="headerlink" title="Library"></a>Library</h2><p>Students can easily access information online, so libraries are no longer necessary. To what extent do you agree or disagree?</p><h3 id="Mind-Mapping-2"><a href="#Mind-Mapping-2" class="headerlink" title="Mind Mapping"></a>Mind Mapping</h3><p><img src="/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/Library.png" alt="Library"></p><h3 id="Words-or-Sentences-2"><a href="#Words-or-Sentences-2" class="headerlink" title="Words or Sentences"></a>Words or Sentences</h3><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">Second:</span><br><span class="line">There is no denying (不可否认的是) that the number of library users is declining, as most information searchers have turned to the Internet, the biggest source of information.</span><br><span class="line">people are able to learn all subjects and read various books with the click of a mouse，without the limitations of time and place.</span><br><span class="line">Third and fourth:</span><br><span class="line">quiet environment</span><br><span class="line">Despite the popularity of online reading these days, some people still prefer to read print books.The touch of paper gives them peace of mind,which can give them a different experience than reading on the electronic device.</span><br><span class="line">This offers us an opportunity to befriend with them just because of reading the same book like &quot;（书名）The Old Man and the Sea&quot;​</span><br><span class="line">socialise //社交</span><br><span class="line">interact with //互动</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>IELTS</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2022/06/30/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2022/06/30/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo server</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo generate</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo deploy</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
