<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Speaking for IELTS</title>
    <link href="/2022/06/30/Speaking-for-IELTS/"/>
    <url>/2022/06/30/Speaking-for-IELTS/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Person"><a href="#Person" class="headerlink" title="Person"></a>Person</h1><h2 id="famous-person"><a href="#famous-person" class="headerlink" title="famous person"></a>famous person</h2><h3 id="Mind"><a href="#Mind" class="headerlink" title="Mind"></a>Mind</h3><ol><li>描述人物：职业、外貌、第一次如何知道他</li><li>人物生平：出名前、出名中（因何而出名）、出名后（现状）</li><li>看法：feeling + eg</li></ol><h3 id="Messi"><a href="#Messi" class="headerlink" title="Messi"></a>Messi</h3><p>I would like to talk about Lionel Messi, the only player who has won a 7-time Ballon d’Or<sup id="fnref:1" class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote"><span class="hint--top hint--rounded" aria-label="金球奖">[1]</span></a></sup>.On the court, where professional players average about 183 in height, Messi looks so small at 170, but no one dares to ignore his role on the court. As for how I first got to know him, I still remember it. That happened in the 2007 season, Barcelona against Real Madrid, where 19 Messi scored his first career hat-trick.</p><p>Messi, whom we often know now, is the top player who has won 10 La Liga titles and 4 Champions League titles. But not many people know that when Messi was young, he almost gave up football because of a lack of growth hormone, but thanks to Barca’s timely intervention, which helped Messi pay for high treatment costs, the football player showed talent in the days to come. The fame and money that football brings has not addicted him to live a luxury and dissipation life. He is passionate about philanthropy and the construction of football in his hometown.</p><p>There are two reasons why l am interested in him. Firstly,l am obsessed with his superb football skills,which  is extremely watchable. Just like what l said before he is born for soccer. Secondly, his humility and unafraid of challenges inspire me. Peach and plum don’t say anything, but they are self-made<sup id="fnref:2" class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote"><span class="hint--top hint--rounded" aria-label="桃李不言，下自成蹊">[2]</span></a></sup>.In the end, I sincerely wish him to win the FIFA World Cup Trophy<sup id="fnref:3" class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote"><span class="hint--top hint--rounded" aria-label="大力神杯">[3]</span></a></sup> in this year.</p><iframe src="../../../../slide.html" width="100%" height="500" name="topFrame" scrolling="yes" noresize="noresize" frameborder="0" id="topFrame"></iframe><h3 id="Professor-Tang"><a href="#Professor-Tang" class="headerlink" title="Professor Tang"></a>Professor Tang</h3><p>l would like to talk about Professor Tang Yu. Perhaps he is not well known among the ordinary people of our country, but in our field of expertise he is a highly respected scholar. He is tall and slim, always wearing a pair of black-rimmed glasses, a standard scholarly demeanor. The first time I met him was in my junior year of college, where he taught us a course on big data science and technology. </p><p>Like many academics, he also studied abroad at a young age. After receiving his Ph.D. from MIT, he chose to return to China and eventually came to our school to teach. He is fascinated by the front-end technology of big data science , published many papers at home and abroad, and won the first prize of national science and technology.</p><p>Although he is a long-established professor, he is humble in class. Since learning about big data for the first time, I often asked him questions. These questions that may seem like idiots to him, but he were patiently answered for me. At the same time, his profound knowledge also deeply influenced me, so that I finally chose the path of big data science, and he was the guide on my learning path.</p><section class="footnotes"><div class="footnote-list"><ol><li><span id="fn:1" class="footnote-text"><span>金球奖<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref"> ↩</a></span></span></li><li><span id="fn:2" class="footnote-text"><span>桃李不言，下自成蹊<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref"> ↩</a></span></span></li><li><span id="fn:3" class="footnote-text"><span>大力神杯<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref"> ↩</a></span></span></li></ol></div></section>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>IELTS</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>writing for IELTS</title>
    <link href="/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/"/>
    <url>/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Internet"><a href="#Internet" class="headerlink" title="Internet"></a>Internet</h1><h2 id="Media"><a href="#Media" class="headerlink" title="Media"></a>Media</h2><p>More and more people no longer read newspaper or watch TV programs to get news. They get news about the world through the internet. Is this a positive or negative development ?</p><h3 id="Mind-Mapping"><a href="#Mind-Mapping" class="headerlink" title="Mind Mapping"></a>Mind Mapping</h3><p><img src="/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/Media.png" alt="Media"></p><h3 id="Words-or-Sentences"><a href="#Words-or-Sentences" class="headerlink" title="Words or Sentences"></a>Words or Sentences</h3><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">First:</span><br><span class="line">While I accept that surfing the internet to read news can sometimes have a positive effect on the user, I believe that it is more likely to have a harmful impact. </span><br><span class="line">Second:</span><br><span class="line">fragmented time //碎片化时间 like wolking time,have dinner in a restaurant and so on.</span><br><span class="line">The web is rich in resources, and you can search for more news you want to know. </span><br><span class="line">Internet does a great job in accelerating the circulation（加速传播） of the news.</span><br><span class="line">Third and fourth:</span><br><span class="line">Electrical newspapers make it a much more difficult thing to have deep reading and thorough thinking as they advocate fast and superficial reading with enormous information, while printed ones encourage slow and deep reading with proper amounts of exact information.</span><br><span class="line">To be specific, many pieces of news appearing on the Internet are inaccurate and unreliable, even the coverage towards the same event differs largely, which will consume readers or viewers a large amount of time and energy to ascertain the authenticity（确认真实性） of the news. By contrast, based on careful authorized steps and censorship（授权步骤和审查）, most of the resources from newspapers and TV programs are confirmed and dependable. Not to mention that traditional media can help people access the in-depth reports（深度报道）.</span><br><span class="line">Fifh:</span><br><span class="line">All in all, Internet has certainly revolutionised news propagation, but not all of the outcomes of this revolution have been positive.To some degree, getting news through printed newspapers or television are still irreplaceable.</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="Security-and-Convenience"><a href="#Security-and-Convenience" class="headerlink" title="Security and Convenience"></a>Security and Convenience</h2><h3 id="Mind-Mapping-1"><a href="#Mind-Mapping-1" class="headerlink" title="Mind Mapping"></a>Mind Mapping</h3><p><img src="/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/securityandconvenience.png" alt="securityandconvenience"></p><h3 id="Words-or-Sentences-1"><a href="#Words-or-Sentences-1" class="headerlink" title="Words or Sentences"></a>Words or Sentences</h3><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br><span class="line">16</span><br><span class="line">17</span><br><span class="line">18</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">First:</span><br><span class="line">Opinions on a digital society has been contradictory with severe tension and incompatibility between the concerns for data privacy and the pursuit of convenience.</span><br><span class="line">Second:</span><br><span class="line">vulnerability //弱点,攻击</span><br><span class="line">manipulate vt. 熟练操作</span><br><span class="line">hack into vi. 侵入（他人的计算机系统）</span><br><span class="line">vigilance n. 警惕（性）</span><br><span class="line">elaborate adj. 精心制作的</span><br><span class="line">fraud n. 诈骗</span><br><span class="line">Many argue that sensitive information registered online leads to the vulnerability of personal security and constant harassment. </span><br><span class="line">A minute after you browse certain applications, you get a call promoting their products immediately, and on a continuous basis. These side effects are eating up the benefits it can bring.</span><br><span class="line">Third and fourth:</span><br><span class="line">give up eating for fear of chocking.</span><br><span class="line">Simply a swipe on the phone allows us to pay without cash, to have the goods delivered to the door, and to keep in frequent contact with friends thousand miles away.</span><br><span class="line">Especially against the backdrop of the long-lasting pandemic, it is impossible to go anywhere without the green health code and travel records. </span><br><span class="line">Therefore, putting personal particulars online has become an irreversible trend, not only as the pathway towards personal convenience but also the necessity for social development.</span><br><span class="line">Fifh:</span><br><span class="line">In conclusion, I strongly believe that the advantages of storing personal information online have exceeded the risks and it complies with the requirement of social advancement.</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Education"><a href="#Education" class="headerlink" title="Education"></a>Education</h1><h2 id="Library"><a href="#Library" class="headerlink" title="Library"></a>Library</h2><p>Students can easily access information online, so libraries are no longer necessary. To what extent do you agree or disagree?</p><h3 id="Mind-Mapping-2"><a href="#Mind-Mapping-2" class="headerlink" title="Mind Mapping"></a>Mind Mapping</h3><p><img src="/2022/06/30/writing-for-IELTS/Library.png" alt="Library"></p><h3 id="Words-or-Sentences-2"><a href="#Words-or-Sentences-2" class="headerlink" title="Words or Sentences"></a>Words or Sentences</h3><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">Second:</span><br><span class="line">There is no denying (不可否认的是) that the number of library users is declining, as most information searchers have turned to the Internet, the biggest source of information.</span><br><span class="line">people are able to learn all subjects and read various books with the click of a mouse，without the limitations of time and place.</span><br><span class="line">Third and fourth:</span><br><span class="line">quiet environment</span><br><span class="line">Despite the popularity of online reading these days, some people still prefer to read print books.The touch of paper gives them peace of mind,which can give them a different experience than reading on the electronic device.</span><br><span class="line">This offers us an opportunity to befriend with them just because of reading the same book like &quot;（书名）The Old Man and the Sea&quot;​</span><br><span class="line">socialise //社交</span><br><span class="line">interact with //互动</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>IELTS</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2022/06/30/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2022/06/30/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo server</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo generate</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo deploy</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
